{
  "title": "5.12",
  "definitions": {
    "DICTATORIAL": {
      "word": "DICTATORIAL",
      "phonetic": "(dik-tÔøΩtor'-E-ÔøΩI)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">like a DICTATOR, overbearing, oppressive </p><p>A DICTATOR is a person who rules a country by himself, usually in a cruel way. DICTATORIAL is the adjective from DICTATOR and means “like a DICTATOR.”  The word suggests a person who is so used to power that he expects everyone to obey him. </p><p>“Her father’s DICTATORIAL attitude bothered Cathy. He would punish her if she didn’t obey him immediately.” </p><p>“The teacher believes you don’t have to be DICTATORIAL to make students learn. Being pleasant and understanding often works better.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: DICTATOR, n.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-al</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "RELISH": {
      "word": "RELISH",
      "phonetic": "(rel'-ish)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to enjoy, take delight in </p><p>To RELISH something is to enjoy it greatly, to take delight in it. </p><p>“They RELISH singing. They sing every chance they get.” </p><p>“I RELISH the idea of going to camp this summer.” </p><p>“I don’t RELISH the thought of having to sweep the floor.” </p><p>RELISH is also a noun, meaning enjoyment. </p><p>“She led the parade with great RELISH.” </p><p>“I have little RELISH for getting up so early.”</p>"
    },
    "DON": {
      "word": "DON",
      "phonetic": "(don)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to put on, dress in </p><p>DON is used about clothing, and means to <i class=“def-ital\">put on.</i> </p><p>“The king DONNED his finest robes when he went to meet them.” </p><p>“She DONNED a brand new hat for Easter.” </p><p>“Jane DONNED her favorite gown to go to the dance.” </p><p>Most people who get this word wrong on the Pretest choose <i class=“def-ital\">take off</i> as its meaning. This is the exact opposite of DON. A similar-sounding word, <i class=“def-ital\">doff,</i> means to <i class=“def-ital\">take off,</i> and this may cause some of the confusion. “He DONNED his coat when he went outside, then <i class=“def-ital\">doffed</i> it when he came back in again.” Usage: DON is a rather old-fashioned word and would not usually be used in ordinary conversation.</p>"
    },
    "LIVELIHOOD": {
      "word": "LIVELIHOOD",
      "phonetic": "(llv'-IE-hud)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a means of support, living </p><p>A LIVELIHOOD is a way of making a living, a means of earning money. The word can apply to the money you earn in order to live, or to the job or career from which you earn the money. </p><p>“He gained his LIVELIHOOD by selling from door to door.” </p><p>“Raising sheep provided them with a decent LIVELIHOOD.” </p><p>Many people think LIVELIHOOD means <i class=“def-ital\">hobby.</i> A <i class=“def-ital\">hobby</i> is something you do for fun, though, not to make a living. </p><p>“Her parent didn’t mind acting as a <i class=“def-ital\">hobby,</i> but they disapproved of it as a LIVELIHOOD.”</p>"
    },
    "ASSERT": {
      "word": "ASSERT",
      "phonetic": "(ÔøΩsert')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to declare, state, affirm, maintain </p><p>To ASSERT something is to state positively that it is true, usually without proof. </p><p>“The defendant ASSERTED his innocence.” </p><p>“Father ASSERTED that we were too young to see that movie.” </p><p>“John ASSERTED that he was strong enough to carry the box.” </p><p>In a similar sense, ASSERT means “to put forward boldly.” “If you want people to pay attention to you, you must ASSERT yourself\"—that is, you must demand to be recognized or listened to. </p><p>The most common mistake is to choose <i class=“def-ital\">believe</i> as the meaning of ASSERT. You would usually <i class=“def-ital\">believe</i> something that you ASSERT, but ASSERT adds the idea of declaring your belief publicly and forcefully. Other forms of the word: ASSERTION, n. ASSERTIVE, adj.</p>"
    },
    "INVOKE": {
      "word": "INVOKE",
      "phonetic": "(in-vOk')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to call upon, call for, appeal to, entreat, summon </p><p> The <i class=“def-ital\">voke</i> part of the word means to <i class=“def-ital\">call.</i> To <i class=“def-ital\">revoke</i> is to call back, to <i class=“def-ital\">convoke</i> is to call together, to <i class=“def-ital\">evoke</i> is to call forth. INVOKE has several different uses, all of which basically mean to <i class=“def-ital\">call in</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">call upon.</i> To INVOKE God’s name is to call upon it—for example, in support of what you are saying. To INVOKE someone’s mercy is to call for it, to beg for it. To INVOKE an investigation is to cause it, to call it forth. To INVOKE evil spirits is to call them forth, to summon them by magic. </p><p>Other forms of the word: INVOCATION, n.</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">in-1</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "UTILITY": {
      "word": "UTILITY",
      "phonetic": "(yU-til'-::l-tE)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">usefulness </p><p>UTILITY is the quality of being useful, the ability to be of use. </p><p>“This invention might not have much UTILITY right away, but in a few years it will be very useful.” </p><p>“The teachers had an argument over the UTILITY of teaching arithmetic this way.” </p><p>A “public UTILITY” is a company that supplies an essential public service like water or electricity. </p><p>To UTILIZE something is to make use of it. </p><p>“Bill UTILIZED many old pieces of lumber in building the barn.” </p><p>“She has so many talents that it is difficult for her to UTILIZE them all.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: UTILIZE, v.</p>"
    },
    "PARTITION": {
      "word": "PARTITION",
      "phonetic": "(pahr-tish'-gn)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to divide, split, separate into parts </p><p>You can see the word <i class=“def-ital\">part</i> in PARTITION. PARTITION means “to split or separate into parts.” The word can be used with almost anything that can be made into smaller spaces. </p><p>“After World War II, Germany was PARTITIONED into East Germany and West Germany.” </p><p>“They PARTITIONED the living room to allow for a dining area.” </p><p>“The box is PARTITIONED to hold different sizes of bottles.” </p><p>A PARTITION is something that divides or separates. </p><p>“They used movable PARTITIONS to create separate offices in the large open space.”</p>"
    },
    "GROPE": {
      "word": "GROPE",
      "phonetic": "(grOp)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to feel about blindly, feel one’s way, search blindly or uncertainly </p><p>To GROPE for something is to feel about for it as if you were blind and could only use your hands. </p><p>“He GROPED for the flashlight in the dark.” </p><p>“She GROPED for the ball that had rolled beneath the couch.” </p><p>“They GROPED their way through the dark tunnel.” </p><p>GROPE is also used in a more general sense for any kind of uncertain or hesitant search. </p><p>“He GROPED for an answer to the difficult math problem.” </p><p>“She GROPED for the proper words to say how thankful she was.”</p>"
    },
    "FALLACY": {
      "word": "FALLACY",
      "phonetic": "(fal'-::l-sE)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a false or mistaken idea; false reasoning </p><p>In logic, a FALLACY is an incorrect line of reasoning which leads to a mistaken conclusion. For example, the following is a FALLACY: </p><p>“If a man is shot through the head, he will die. Smith died; therefore he was shot through the head.” </p><p>Being shot through the head is obviously not the only way a man can die. A particular error in logic has been made which makes the conclusion false. These errors are called, in general, FALLACIES. </p><p>In everyday use, a FALLACY is an idea which is false or mistaken, usually because of faulty reasoning. </p><p>“The theory that boys are smarter than girls has repeatedly been shown to be a FALLACY.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: FALLACIOUS, adj.</p>"
    },
    "REPRIMAND": {
      "word": "REPRIMAND",
      "phonetic": "(rep'-rÔøΩmand)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to scold, rebuke, censure, reprove </p><p>To REPRIMAND someone is to scold him severely for having done something wrong. </p><p>“Her parents REPRIMANDED her for staying out so late without permission.” </p><p>REPRIMAND usually has the sense of an official, formal censure. </p><p>“The soldier was officially REPRIMANDED for not following orders.” </p><p>REPRIMAND is also a noun. </p><p>“The president of the company sent him a letter of REPRIMAND for missing work.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Arrest</i> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer. REPRIMANDING a person falls far short of <i class=“def-ital\">arresting</i> him and putting him in jail, however.</p>"
    },
    "PRESUMPTUOUS": {
      "word": "PRESUMPTUOUS",
      "phonetic": "(pri-zuhmp'-chU-as)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">overconfident, arrogant, audacious </p><p>To PRESUME to do something is to dare to do it, to take the liberty of doing it. </p><p>“The bold soldier PRESUMED to call the general by his first name.” Someone who is PRESUMPTUOUS PRESUMES too much. He is too bold and confident and assumes he has the right to do things when he really hasn’t.  </p><p>“It was PRESUMPTUOUS of him to think that I would go along with whatever he decided.” </p><p>“The PRESUMPTUOUS assistant decided he knew what to do and wouldn’t wait for the boss’s orders.” </p><p>“He was never PRESUMPTUOUS, but always waited patiently for the permission of his superiors to do anything.” </p><p>The most commonly chosen incorrect answer is <i class=“def-ital\">impolite.</i> PRESUMPTUOUS people might often be <i class=“def-ital\">impolite,</i> but PRESUMPTUOUS has a much more specific meaning than that. Other forms of the word: PRESUME, v. PRESUMPTION, n.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-ous</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "HURTLE": {
      "word": "HURTLE",
      "phonetic": "(her'-tÔøΩI)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to rush violently, move rapidly; to drive, fling </p><p>To HURTLE is to move rapidly and violently. The word usually emphasizes speed, noise, and violence. </p><p>“Tons of snow HURTLED down the mountainside during the avalanche.” </p><p>“The rocket HURTLED through the air at five times the speed of sound.” </p><p>To HURTLE something is to drive it forward rapidly or violently. </p><p>“The new train HURTLED its passengers across the country in record time.”</p>"
    },
    "TALON": {
      "word": "TALON",
      "phonetic": "(tal'-ÔøΩn)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a claw </p><p>A TALON is a <i class=“def-ital\">claw,</i> especially the claw of a bird of prey like a hawk. </p><p>“The eagle swooped down and seized the rabbit in its TALONS.” </p><p>“The bird curved its TALONS around its perch.”</p>"
    },
    "ENDEAVCR": {
      "word": "ENDEAVCR",
      "phonetic": "(en-dev'-3r)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to try, make an effort, attempt, strive </p><p>ENDEAVOR means to <i class=“def-ital\">try.</i> The word usually adds to <i class=“def-ital\">try</i> a sense of determined effort or struggle. </p><p>“No matter how much they ENDEAVORED, they couldn’t finish in time.” </p><p>“They ENDEAVORED to clean up the house before their mother returned.” </p><p>ENDEAVOR when used as a noun emphasizes even more strongly this idea of difficulty and determination. </p><p>“They made a serious ENDEAVOR to solve these important problems.” </p><p>“The ENDEAVOR was worthwhile, even if it did not succeed.”</p>"
    }
  },
  "id": "12",
  "exercises": [
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "DICTATORIAL manner.",
          "answers": [
            "meek",
            "convincing",
            "royal",
            "overbearing",
            "businesslike"
          ],
          "word": "DICTATORIAL",
          "correct": "overbearing"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We RELISH it.",
          "answers": [
            "dislike",
            "need",
            "study",
            "approve of",
            "enjoy"
          ],
          "word": "RELISH",
          "correct": "enjoy"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DON the coat.",
          "answers": [
            "put on",
            "finish",
            "brush",
            "take off",
            "choose"
          ],
          "word": "DON",
          "correct": "put on"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Typical LIVELIHOOD.",
          "answers": [
            "fast dance",
            "hobby",
            "criminal",
            "investment",
            "means of support"
          ],
          "word": "LIVELIHOOD",
          "correct": "means of support"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To ASSERT that it is true.",
          "answers": [
            "believe",
            "pretend",
            "hope",
            "declare",
            "deny"
          ],
          "word": "ASSERT",
          "correct": "declare"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INVOKE his mercy.",
          "answers": [
            "hope for",
            "expect",
            "call upon",
            "accept",
            "refuse"
          ],
          "word": "INVOKE",
          "correct": "call upon"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Discussed its UTILITY.",
          "answers": [
            "power",
            "usefulness",
            "importance",
            "result",
            "uselessness"
          ],
          "word": "UTILITY",
          "correct": "usefulness"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They PARTITIONED the area.",
          "answers": [
            "divided",
            "sought",
            "destroyed",
            "united",
            "surrounded"
          ],
          "word": "PARTITION",
          "correct": "divided"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GROPE for them.",
          "answers": [
            "go out",
            "wish",
            "ask angrily",
            "feel blindly",
            "wait"
          ],
          "word": "GROPE",
          "correct": "feel blindly"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A common FALLACY.",
          "answers": [
            "false idea",
            "understanding",
            "lie",
            "old saying",
            "truth"
          ],
          "word": "FALLACY",
          "correct": "false idea"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We must REPRIMAND him.",
          "answers": [
            "arrest",
            "forbid",
            "scold",
            "reward",
            "honor"
          ],
          "word": "REPRIMAND",
          "correct": "scold"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PRESUMPTUOUS people.",
          "answers": [
            "timid",
            "rich",
            "quick-witted",
            "overconfident",
            "nasty"
          ],
          "word": "PRESUMPTUOUS",
          "correct": "overconfident"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HURTLE down the street.",
          "answers": [
            "walk slowly",
            "crawl",
            "look quickly",
            "rush violently",
            "hop"
          ],
          "word": "HURTLE",
          "correct": "rush violently"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Examined the TALON.",
          "answers": [
            "claw",
            "lawyer",
            "wing",
            "beak",
            "criminal"
          ],
          "word": "TALON",
          "correct": "claw"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENDEAVOR to serve.",
          "answers": [
            "hope",
            "try",
            "remember",
            "refuse",
            "like"
          ],
          "word": "ENDEAVCR",
          "correct": "try"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-one",
      "id": "pretest"
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Is a DICTATORIAL boss fun to work for?",
          "word": "DICTATORIAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most people RELISH the idea of going hungry?",
          "word": "RELISH",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would you DON your shoes when you're going to bed?",
          "word": "DON",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a person who is unemployed have a good LIVELIHOOD?",
          "word": "LIVELIHOOD",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could a person ASSERT that something is true when it really isn't?",
          "word": "ASSERT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a witch INVOKE evil spirits?",
          "word": "INVOKE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does an automobile have any UTILITY?",
          "word": "UTILITY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a desk drawer be PARTITIONED?",
          "word": "PARTITION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a person GROPE for words?",
          "word": "GROPE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Should you believe a FALLACY?",
          "word": "FALLACY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would you REPRIMAND someone for being a hero?",
          "word": "REPRIMAND",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do PRESUMPTUOUS people think they know a lot?",
          "word": "PRESUMPTUOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do turtles usually HURTLE?",
          "word": "HURTLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do fish have TALONS?",
          "word": "TALON",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do runners ENDEAVOR to break records?",
          "word": "ENDEAVOR",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 1
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "The DICTATORIAL secretary was extremely fast at taking shorthand.",
          "word": "DICTATORIAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He told the story of his opponent's arrest with obvious RELISH.",
          "word": "RELISH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Jack DONNED his new suit for his first day on the job.",
          "word": "DON",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He lost his LIVELIHOOD when the factory closed down.",
          "word": "LIVELIHOOD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The patriot openly ASSERTED his love for his country.",
          "word": "ASSERT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They INVOKED Bill's license because of his many speeding tickets.",
          "word": "INVOKE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We'll never UTILIZE all this equipment. You'll have to take some back.",
          "word": "UTILITY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They PARTITIONED us to come with them.",
          "word": "PARTITION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Joe GROPED in the closet for the old pair of shoes.",
          "word": "GROPE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He said the belief that airlines were unsafe was a FALLACY.",
          "word": "FALLACY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "You will only receive a REPRIMAND this time; next time you will be put in jail.",
          "word": "REPRIMAND",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was PRESUMPTUOUS of you to think you could take the car without asking me first.",
          "word": "PRESUMPTUOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The kitten HURTLED across the room when it saw its supper being prepared.",
          "word": "HURTLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The bird curved its TALONS around the thin branch.",
          "word": "TALON",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The ENDEAVOR to put a man on the moon was finally successful.",
          "word": "ENDEAVCR",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 2
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "DICTATORIAL",
          "answers": [
            "dominating",
            "tyrannical",
            "studious"
          ],
          "word": "DICTATORIAL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RELISH",
          "answers": [
            "satisfaction",
            "delight",
            "understanding"
          ],
          "word": "RELISH",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DON",
          "answers": [
            "wear",
            "dress",
            "bury"
          ],
          "word": "DON",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LIVELIHOOD",
          "answers": [
            "earnings",
            "career",
            "hobby"
          ],
          "word": "LIVELIHOOD",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ASSERT",
          "answers": [
            "expect",
            "insist",
            "claim"
          ],
          "word": "ASSERT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INVOKE",
          "answers": [
            "summon",
            "remember",
            "appeal"
          ],
          "word": "INVOKE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "UTILITY",
          "answers": [
            "value",
            "suitability",
            "comedy"
          ],
          "word": "UTILITY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PARTITION",
          "answers": [
            "cut",
            "separate",
            "destroy"
          ],
          "word": "PARTITION",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GROPE",
          "answers": [
            "feel",
            "throw",
            "search"
          ],
          "word": "GROPE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FALLACY",
          "answers": [
            "falsehood",
            "exception",
            "mistake"
          ],
          "word": "FALLACY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REPRIMAND",
          "answers": [
            "kill",
            "criticize",
            "blame"
          ],
          "word": "REPRIMAND",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PRESUMPTUOUS",
          "answers": [
            "vain",
            "bold",
            "stupid"
          ],
          "word": "PRESUMPTUOUS",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HURTLE",
          "answers": [
            "worry",
            "rush",
            "drive"
          ],
          "word": "HURTLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TALON",
          "answers": [
            "toe",
            "knee",
            "claw"
          ],
          "word": "TALON",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENDEAVOR",
          "answers": [
            "struggle",
            "escape",
            "attempt"
          ],
          "word": "ENDEAVCR",
          "correct": "1"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-all",
      "id": 3
    }
  ]
}